本片为真人真事，片中事件发生于…
1972年8月22日，纽约布鲁克林
热天午后
一定是总部来的
It has to be from downtown.
我们是可以处理，但是需要总部同意
It's handled through this office, but it requires downtown approval.
我不知道
I don't know.
有很多人都碰过
It has been submitted.
苏菲雅，你可否帮我一下忙？
Sylvia, can you help me with this?
来了
Coming.
打烊了，你想进来？
Closing time. Going in?
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
你是经理？
You the manager?
继续讲你的电话
Keep talking like nothing was wrong.
我等下再回你电话
Let me call you back.
桑尼，我有不好的预感
Sonny, I'm getting really bad vibes.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
或许我们应该拿小一点的武器
Maybe we should take something smaller.
你疯啦，枪都拿出来了
You crazy? He started already. He's got the gun out.
快去站在门边
Go on, go over by the door.
站到门边去
Get over by the door.
全都不准动
Freeze!
全都不准动，快点
-Nobody move! -Get over there!
离警报器远点
Get away from those alarms.
靠中间站
Now get in the center.
他要是敢动就打烂他的头
He moves, shoot him!
用枪指着他，站中间点
Put the gun on him! Get out in the center.
桑尼
我没办法，桑尼
I can't do it, Sonny.
什么！
I'm not going to make it.
我下不了手，桑尼
你在讲什么？快指着他
What? Put it on him.
我没办法，桑尼
I can't do it.
我操！沙尔
Fuck me! Sal!
干嘛？　　你在哪儿？他办不到
-What? -Where are you? He can't make it.
去他的，叫他滚
Fuck him. Let him go!
快啊，桑尼
Come on!
让他出去
All right, let him out.
让他出去　　　照着做，哈维
Do what the gentleman says.
让他出去
Let him out.
对不起，桑尼
I'm sorry.
该死
Shit!
别把车开走　　　那我怎么回家？
-Don't take the car. -How do I get home?
坐地铁，我们需要车
Take the subway. We need the car.
车钥匙给我
The keys!
对不起，桑尼
I'm sorry, Sonny.
把门锁上
All right, lock it.
他妈的
What?
那边桌子底下有个女孩
There's a girl under that desk over there.
他总算走了，现在可以办正事
We got rid of him. So now we just move it along.
听到了吗？
You got them?
他刚跟我说什么？
Now what did he say to me? Wait a minute.
谁躲在这里？这是什么，松鼠吗？
Anybody here? What's this, a squirrel?
喂…
Hey, you!
快点
Come on.
你出来站到后面去，没人会伤害你的
In the back there. No one's going to hurt you.
快点，你站在后面去
Go ahead, get to the back.
把窗帘拉起来
Pull the drapes!
你站在后面去
You, to the back here.
到那边去
Go to him, right there.
速战速决，快！
We're going to move this now. Just move it along.
好
Gotcha!
速战速决，快！我们三十分钟内要完成
We're moving right along, folks. Going to get this thing done in half an hour.
我只是要…
We just got to block....
遮住监视器
Knock out the TV.
好了
There we go.
你看
See?
没录影也没警报器
No replay, folks. No alarms.
你们拿了东西可以走人了吧？
Let's get you fixed up and on your way.
金库开了没？　　这我来处理
-Is the vault open? -I can take care of that.
好，你来处理
Good. Let's go. Take care of it.
等一下，你在做什么？
Wait! What are you trying to do?
想启动警报器吗？用这把钥匙？
Trip the alarm? Use the spot key?
我一时忘了
I was out of my mind.
听好
Get your mind right!
我是个天主教徒，我不想伤害任何人，懂吗？
I'm a Catholic. I don't want to hurt anybody!
是的，先生　　　不准按警报器
-Yes, sir. -No alarms.
不准按警报器
No alarms!
少玩把戏
No games.
用另一把钥匙
Use the other one.
玛莉安
Miriam...
把保险柜打开
...open the safe.
把钱放进袋子里
Put it in this.
怎样？
What?
只有这些
That's all there is.
你胡说什么？
What are you saying?
下午有人把钱收走了，这里只剩1100元
They picked it up today. There's only $1 ,1 00.
她说的是真的　　　别杀我
-It's true. -He'll shoot me!
我不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it!
竟然会没有钱
There's no money here.
桑尼，快点拿钱　　　我在拿了…
-Come on, Sonny, let's do it! -I'm doing it!
怎么会这样？…
Too much! This is too much.
好了，我们走
All right, come on. Let's go.
电话，你去接，沙尔，看好他
You answer it. Watch him, Sal.
你跟我来
You, come with me. Watch him!
坐下　　　谁是这儿的领班？
-Sit down. -Who's the head teller here?
是我
I am.
把这打开
Open it up.
不要全部拿
No, not all of it.
我在银行做过事，别以为我不知道警报器藏在哪
I worked in a bank. I know the alarms. All right?
别耍花招
Don't play games with me.
你得这样做
You take one of these, go like this...
先放进去再拿出来
...in here, and out it comes.
一百块就到手了
You got your 1 00.
我再回你电话
I'll call back.
不行，这张是废物，因为有记号
No, it's decoy money. It's marked.
这是狗屎
It's shit.
看？
See?
高兴点，以后抢银行你就有经验了
Cheer up, you'll be the veterans of a robbery.
银行会给你一打玫瑰花的
You know the bank sends you a dozen red roses?
沙尔，叫经理接电话
Let him answer it.
嘿，经理，别打任何馊主意
Fucker! Don't get ideas.
我会叫，那边那个会咬
I bark, that man there...he bites!
相信我，我是你们这一边
I'm on your side.
我们这边？鬼才信
On my side, shit!
我们这有年轻的少女，请注意你说话的字眼
Listen, we got young girls here. You could watch your language.
我想说什么就说什么
I speak what I feel.
注意用词？清光那抽屉
Watch my language! Empty the drawer out.
我不知道，你可能要问他
You'd have to find out from him.
旅行支票
Traveler's checks...
还有登记簿
...and register.
登记簿
The register!
好了，走吧
You've got it. All right, let's go.
这我来拿
I'll take that from you.
沙尔，我们走吧
All right, Sal, here we go.
可恶
Come on.
桑尼，你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我在烧登记簿
I'm burning the register here.
所有人往前走
Moving right along, folks.
我们要走了
We're leaving.
把钥匙给我
Let me have the keys.
哈维，把钥匙给他
Give him the keys.
我们不会伤害你的，我们要走了
Nobody will hurt you. We're going to leave.
桑尼，那是谁？
Who's that?
他是对面的保险业务员，大概是看到烟了
The insurance guy from across the street. He probably saw the smoke.
请把火扑灭
Please, put out the fire.
我去拿水　　　站着别动
I'll get water.
Stay right there!
我待会儿回你电话　　　打发他！
-Call you later. -Get rid of him!
打发他！
Get rid of him!
别动歪脑筋，我来处理
-Use your head. -I can handle it.
一切还好吧？　　没事，只是垃圾桶里的烟蒂
-Everything's all right? -Cigarette butt got in the wastebasket.
你们没事
Then you're okay.
谢谢你帮我们留意　　　哪里
Thanks for keeping an eye out.
我们所有的钱都给你们了　　　好吧，我们走
-Go now. We gave you all we've got. -Okay, we're going.
接电话，沙尔
Answer the phone.
带他们去金库
Get them in the vault.
钱呢？　　我拿了
-Where's the money? -Getting it! Got it.
他要跟我们一起走
He'll come with us.
拜托别关门，我们还要呼吸
Don't close it. How can we breathe?
等一下，等一下
Wait a minute!
等一下　　　什么事？
-Wait. Listen. -What?
我撑不了的，我必须去厕所
I will never make this. I'll have to go to the toilet.
这不是开玩笑的
It's no joke.
我对幽闭恐惧症
I've got a terrible fear of being locked in.
好吧，还有谁要去？
Who needs the bathroom?
我也要去　　　现在变成全都要去了
I do too.
你可以检查看看
Now they all want to go.
Look, do you want to check it out?
在你右手边的第一间
It's the first door on your right.
好吧，去吧
All right, mouth, let's go.
右手边的第一间
First door on my right.
她是玛丽亚
It's Maria!
我忘了她在这儿
I forgot she was in there.
这不是她的错，她常这样，她只有十分钟休息
She's always pulling this.
常常忘记…　　闭嘴，回去，全都不准去厕所
She should have 10 minutes, but--
Shut up! Nobody goes to the bathroom!
回去，快点　　　现在是银行抢劫
-Let's go. Out! -We're having a bank robbery.
我是马维尼…
Mulvaney speaking.
爱讲话的…
Mouth. Mouth!
这就充当你的马桶　　　你的电话
-Here's your toilet. -It's for you.
什么？
What?
电话是找你的
Phone.
真的
For you.
你在那里做什么？　　你是谁？
-What are you doing? -Who is this?
我是尤金摩瑞提探长，白痴，你们被包围了
Detective Sergeant Eugene Moretti, asshole! We got you by the balls.
不相信的话，看看窗外吧
I'm looking you right on the eye.
我看到你了
I can see you.
是谁？　　条子
-Who is it? -Cops.
把手放在头上走到前门
Come to the front door....
挂掉电话
Hang it up.
快点
Come on, let's go.
怎么会这样？
How'd that happen?
我有伤害你吗？我对你不好吗？
Did I do anything to hurt you? Did I treat you badly?
我的薪水不值得我当英雄　　　这次抢劫有计划吗？
I'm on salary. I won't be a hero.
Did you have a plan or what?
还是你只是突然决定的？
What did you do, barge in on a whim?
你为什么要点火？
Why light a fire?
早就叫你们离开了，不听我的话
I told you to get out...
...when you could, but you had to hang around.
他根本没有计划这次的行动　　　我有计划！
He don't have a plan. It's all a whim. Rob a bank!
只是我以为钱会被送来，而不是被收走
I had it planned!
Only the money should have been delivered, not taken away!
都是那个他妈的杰克，给的错误资讯
That fucking Jack, downtown, he gave me the wrong information.
杰克又是谁啊？幕后的策划人吗？
What is this Jack supposed to be? A mastermind or what?
我们有难同当，我们必须离开这里
We're all in the barrel together and we want to get out of it.
我需要时间思考，让我想想…
All right, I got to have time to think. I got to think.
仔细听好，靠近这里一步
Keep away or we'll start throwing bodies out the door, one at a time. Got that?
我就开始射杀人质一次一个，听到没？
你是谁？
Who is this?
有人叫珍妮吗？
Is there a Jenny here?
谁是珍妮？
Who's Jenny here?
我就是
That's me.
是你这松鼠，有没有先生？
It's the squirrel. You got a husband?
他在电话上
Well, he's on the phone.
接啊
Go ahead.
我要说什么？
What could I tell him?
我不知道，随便你说啊，告诉他详情
I don't know, whatever. Tell him the truth.
真是他妈的闹剧，WNEW，热门音乐电台
What a fucking comedy! W-N-E-W plays all the hits.
听着，先别挂
Listen. Don 't hang up.
里面有人受伤吗？　　没有
-First, is anybody hurt in there? -No.
别靠近，不然我会一个个杀人质，听到吗？
Keep away or we'll start throwing bodies out, one at a time. You got that?
别，等一下，让我跟你聊聊，里面有几个人？
Don't. Let me talk to you for a while. How many people you got?
别问了，你再打给我，你等下再打给我
No, call me back.
Call me back.
他问你们几点会弄完？
He wants to know when you'll be through.
什么？拜托你，小姐
What? Girlie, please!
快上…
Come on. Let's go.
后门在哪儿？　　里面锁住了
-Where's the back door? -It's locked on the inside.
在哪儿？
Where is it?
走廊底的右边
Through the passageway to the right.
沙尔，掩护他们
Cover them!
你随便煮嘛，什么都可以
You could just go ahead and look whatever's there.
好，我会的，我会的
Oh, yes, I will. Yes, I will.
喂，该挂了　　　亲爱的，我得挂了
-Let's go, come on. -Honey, I've got to go now.
我得挂了
I got to go.
我也爱你
I love you too.
现在待在这里面
All right, inside here.
我不知道发生什么事
I don't know what happened.
可能有人不小心触动警报器
Maybe somebody tripped an alarm or something. I don't know.
一定有办法逃出去的，放心好了
But there's a way out of this.
你说的是真的吗？　　什么是真的？
-Were you serious about what you said? -About what?
你真的要…
你真的要射杀人质？
About throwing those bodies out the door?
我只是放风声罢了　　　我只想确认一下
-That's what I want him to think. -I want to know what you think.
因为我已经准备好了
Because I'll tell you right now, I'm ready to do it.
是吗？好吧
Right. Okay.
我是说真的　　　我知道
-I mean it. -I know.
所有人听着，我们现在出了点问题
Listen, everybody. I know we got a problem here.
但是别担心，很快就可以解决
But there's a way out of this thing. I'm telling you.
只要跟我们合作
All you got to do is cooperate with me.
保持镇定，快解决了，听话就不会有人受伤
Stay cool, and we'll get out of this.
Nobody gets hurt if you listen to me.
首先，一步一步来，你要去厕所对吧？
First, we'll do things a step at a time. You got to go to the bathroom, right?
她可以去
She'll get to go to the bathroom.
其他人也可以去，但我们要一起行动
Everybody who has to go is going. We'll do things together, okay?
保持镇静，他怎么了？
What's the matter with him?
他有气喘　　　气喘？
He's got asthma.
Asthma?
我来处理
I'll take care of that.
你叫什么名字？
-You, what's your name? -Mulvaney.
马维尼　　　马维尼？
你跟我来
Come with me.
他有气喘你们还要他当警卫？　　他上过警校
-He's got asthma and he's a guard? -They go to guard school.
学怎么开枪吗？他连枪都没有
To learn how to shoot? He doesn't have a gun.
他们早上升旗，一周可赚150元
They earn a $105 a week to fold the flag in the morning...
我不知道他们学什么
...straighten up. I don't know what they learn.
我要把门挡起来，以免他们冲进来
I want to block that door. In case they try coming in, I can hear it.
过来帮我
Let's move this.
等一下，等一下
Wait a minute. Hold it!
先把这个拿走
Let's get rid of this.
你有小孩吗？
You got kids?
两个，我还想见到他们
I got 2 kids and I'd like to see them again.
别担心，你会的，你一直都还蛮听话的
You'll see them again. You're being cooperative.
我对你没有任何抱怨…没有抱怨…
I got no complaints against you, whatsoever.
一点都没有
Whatsoever. You got bank insurance?
你有没有银行保险？　　你知道我有
你好像蛮清楚银行的事
You know I do. You seem to know a lot about bank procedure.
我还知道很多事
I know a lot of things.
我只是想让你们安全离开，不是吗？
I just want to get you out of here safe, right?
如果我要你跟我走？
What if I take you with me?
如果你要带人的话
If you take anybody...
就选我吧
...please take me.
他们会开枪射你，你知道？
They'll shoot you, you know?
警察
The cops...
他们根本不在乎银行什么保险，看看亚提卡…
...don't care about bank insurance. See what they did in Attica?
他们杀了42人，不管有罪无罪…
42 people killed. The innocent with the guilty.
总之放心
我不会选你的，我要选女人
I won't take you. I'll take one of the girls, a married one with kids.
结婚有小孩的
警察要是杀了她们，见报就不好看了
Cops don't like it in the papers when they shoot a married woman with kids.
尤其是有小孩的
你还不错
You're all right.
你不会跟我玩把戏吧
You won't fuck with me?
调查局的人来了
There's the FBI.
你好吗，沙登？
How you doing, Sheldon?
你为什么不等他们出来呢？
Why didn't you wait and try to take them outside?
我判断错误
An error in judgment.
我以为他们看到警察、听到被包围会吓破胆
Thought the S.O.S would be remorseful at the sight of a policeman.
而且…
And you know something?
没人提及里面有人质
Nobody said "hostage" yet, okay?
发生抢案了
We got a bank robbery here.
记者是怎么突破封锁线的？
How did the press guys get through the barrier?
这次的银行抢案没有任何资讯
We don't know what's up yet. We're setting up communications.
我是CBS的布莱恩，请问现场的状况如何？
This is Ron Cummins from CBS. Can you tell me the situation?
我们在架设通讯设备，嫌犯在里面
We're setting up communications. Our perpetrators are in the bank.
我只能说那么多
That's all I can say now.
有什么我会再跟你们说
When I get it, you'll get it. That's all.
你们在逃生梯那儿干嘛？我是说屋顶
What are you doing on the fire escape?
快上屋顶，可以吗？
I said on the roof. Get up on the roof, will you?
叫电信局了吗？　　全架设完毕
-Get the phone company? -Setting it up now.
这支电话能直接与银行里的人通话
This phone is going to be a direct line into the bank.
我是马维尼　　　我是摩瑞提，让我跟他说话
-Mulvaney speaking. -Moretti here. Let me talk to him.
什么事？　　我是尤金摩瑞提探长
This is Detective Sergeant Eugene Moretti.
现在你们在里面，我们在外面，要怎么办
You're there, we're here. What do we do?
我不知道怎么办
I don't know. What do we do?
首先，我想知道人质都安全吧
Are the people in the bank okay?
是的
They're okay.
你自己一个人还是有同伙？　　我不是一个人
-You alone or you got confederates? -I'm not alone.
还有沙尔　　　沙尔？全名是沙尔瓦多？
I got Sal.
What's that for, Salvatore?
沙尔是个杀手
He's a killer.
我们参加过越战，杀人对我们来说小事一桩
We're Vietnam veterans. Killing don't mean anything to us.
军队里？　　对
-In the army? -Yeah.
你叫什么名字？
So you, what's your name?
你为什么要知道我的名字？
Why do you want to know my name?
我想有个名字称呼你
Just so I got something to call you.
只是给个名字不会怎样的
Let's be reasonable, okay? Just give me your name.
叫我桑尼吧　　　桑尼
Call me Sonny.
听好，桑尼
Listen, Sonny.
我想确认人质的安全　　　嗯
I want to see if the people are okay.
然后我想要跟你商量释放人质的事
Right.
Then I want to work out a way to get them out.
等一下我会不带枪进去里面
I want to come over without a gun.
你可以搜我身，取得你的信任之后
Frisk me so you'll trust me. We'll find a way out of this.
好
I just want to find some way that I can trust you too.
好的，那我该怎么相信你呢？要公平嘛，对不对？
我可不想被枪扫射而死
Not be on the street where you could shoot me.
一些信号？　　没错，像什么？
-Some sign, right? -Right. Like what?
放人质出来如何？
Let the people out.
等一下，你以为我是他妈的白痴啊？
Who do you think you're dealing with? A fucking idiot here?
我才不会放我的护身符出去
They're keeping me alive. Let them out?
干嘛不跟我谈，有话直说　　　好吧，好吧
Talk to me. Just talk to me straight. I'm ready to talk.
那你把女的放出来
Give us the women?
不行，我这儿就只有女的
No, I've got women. That's all I've got.
那就放其中一个
Give me something. Give me one of them.
你要一个干什么？　　公平交易啊
-One? -It's like a fair exchange.
我不会带武器进去，但不会把我当人质吧？
I'll come over. I won't pack nothing, don't know if you'll take me hostage.
表示咱们互相信任嘛
It's a sign of trust.
我怎么跟你连络？　　拿起电话就可以跟我通话
-How do I call you back? -It's a direct line.
拿起电话就可以跟我通话
Pick up the receiver and I'm here.
他要一个人
He wants one.
他，好吗？　　当然好
Him, right?
Right!
可以吗？　　好
他出去
He goes.
对方到底是何方神圣？
What are we dealing with here?
你一定要这样跟着我吗？
You have to keep checking me out all the time?
是的
Yeah.
他需要钥匙
He'll need the keys.
你有吗？
Got the keys?
给他那一支就好，桑尼　　　好啦
Just the one, Sonny!
别开枪，别开枪
Don't fire!
你们在干嘛？
What are you doing?
他是人质耶，让他走
That's a hostage!
别开枪
Don't fire!
Hold your fire!
我们决定让他先出来
We voted to send him out!
他是人质之一！　　放开他！
-He's one of the hostages! -Get away from him!
你们怎么搞的　　　他是人质之一
He's a hostage!
他是人质之一，放开他，你们这是干嘛？
What the hell's the matter with you?
我才不管！离远点！离开
I don't give a fuck! Get out of here.
别挡路，桑尼！等一下
Hey, Sonny! Wait a minute!
桑尼！这就是你的不对
That was your fault, Sonny.
我们之间不是有电话吗？
We had the communications set up here.
我们有250个警察在外面
We're not set up properly, with 250 cops here.
我们不知道，你在里面干什么！
We don't know what goes on in there.
你差点把他杀了，你疯啦！
-You almost killed him! Are you crazy? -That was smart!
真聪明　　　别落井下石，不是说全是女的？
You say you got nothing but women, and throw out a guy. What's going on?
干嘛又放一个男的出来？你搞什么鬼啊！
你不是要人质吗？我给你　　　你要不要合作？
You wanted a hostage, I gave you one.
你要一个人质我就给你一个，不是吗？
-Are you going to deal with us or not? -I gave you one.
但你可以先用电话沟通嘛，出来吧，桑尼
You did, but you should have picked up the phone! Come on out.
我没有带任何武器
I ain't packing nothing, see?
没带任何武器，来搜啊，你一看就知道了
You can come out and frisk me. You can tell.
你要我出去？　　来，我知道你想出来看看…
-Why? -To take a look at something.
我要你知道对手是谁？　　我看得到为何要出去？
-To see what you're up against. -I can see. Why come out?
你出来看啊
Come out and see it all.
来嘛
好不好？
我这有沙尔顾着人质，如果我出事他会知道的
Sal is in there with the other people. Anything happens to me, they'll get it.
我没忘记他，你就出来看嘛
I don't forget about Sal. Come out and look.
出来嘛，好不好？
我要先跟他说　　　好吧，你不用带枪出来
-I got to check with him first. -You don't need that artillery.
桑尼，跟他说只有五分钟
5 minutes. You tell him that.
别紧张
Take it easy.
卡门，叫他们退后，他举白旗了
Get them back. He's got a white flag.
一切都还好
Everything's okay.
出来啊，桑尼
Come on out.
他们太靠近了　　　退后，妈的，你们在做什么？
He's too close here.
Get back! What the fuck are you doing?
退后！退后！可以吗？　　叫他们退后
出来啊，你过来看看
Come on out.
来啊，你看
Take a look at this.
看上面那边
Here, look! Look up here.
还有那边
Over here.
还有那边，我们应有尽有
Over there, right? We got everything here, okay?
整个军队都出动了啊？
You got the militia here.
叫沙尔也出来看看吧！
Let Sal come look. What hope have you got?
看看我们有些什么
见好就收吧
Quit while you're ahead.
趁现在只是企图抢劫而已　　　持枪抢劫
-It's only attempted robbery. -Armed robbery.
好啦，持枪抢劫
All right, armed, then! Nobody's been hurt.
但没有人受伤
你把人质放了
Release the hostages. No one will worry over kidnapping charges.
不会被加上绑架的罪名
最多判五年，但一年就可以假释了　　　亲我
At the most you'll get 5 years. You'll get out in 1 .
什么？　　亲我
-What? -Kiss me.
当我被耍时，我需要有人亲我
When I'm being fucked, I like to get kissed on the mouth.
别这样嘛…　　你是市内的警察吧？
You're a city cop, right? Bank robbery's a federal offense.
抢银行犯法，他们会以绑架、持枪抢劫起诉我
They got me on kidnapping, armed robbery. They'll bury me.
我才不跟要想耍我的人讲话，叫负责人出来
I won't talk to somebody trying to con me. Get someone in charge.
我就是　　　我不要跟你这死肥猪谈判
I won't talk to some flunky pig trying to con me. What's he doing?
他在干嘛？　　退后！你们靠近干嘛？
-Get back! -Why are they moving in?
他们一直靠近是怎样！　　你们退后！退回去！
Will you get the fuck back there?
回去！　　退回去！
Get over there!
退回去！　　他很想尝尝杀我的滋味
Go on back there, man!
He wants to kill me so bad!
我们不杀任何人　　　亚提卡…
-No one's going to kill anybody. -Attica!
亚提卡…
Attica!
别忘了亚提卡事件！
Remember Attica!
你们说话跟放屁一样！
Your word don't fucking matter!
冷静点！
Come on, calm down.
把枪放下
Put your guns down!
如果不是有记者，我们早就被杀光了
Without the TV guys, they'd kill us all!
叫他们把枪放下！
Put your guns down!
他妈的，把枪放下
枪放下
Put them down!
把枪放下
亚提卡
Attica!
就是这样！这样才对嘛…
You got it, man!
抢银行？
Robbing a bank?
他为什么不跟我说他要钱？
Why didn't he tell me he needed money?
他应该跟我说的
He should have come to me if he needed money.
据了解，现在里面有8名人质
We know that 8 people are still being held on the bank.
我们对里面的状况完全不清楚
The situation inside the bank is totally unknown to us other than...
除了被释放人质哈维卡文所提供的描述以外外
...descriptions that have been obtained from Howard Calvin.
你妈是个吸金女，干嘛还抢银行？
Why steal when your mom's a sucker?
现在将镜头带到布鲁克林现场
We'll switch you now to Ron Cummons at the bank on Brooklyn.
班森小姐，请问里面情况如何？
Miss Benson, what's it like inside?
能说什么？就是抢劫嘛！他们在里面
They're holding up, what can I say?
有共识了吗？　　叫沙尔的人…
Got a deal?
拿着枪，不太说话
The guy with the gun on us is a quiet type.
你们相信摩瑞提探长吗？
Any confidence in Detective Moretti?
他们不知道摩瑞提探长…我得走了
They don't know Detective Moretti yet. I got to go now.
你抓我手干嘛？
What's this with the hands?
她都出来了…
She's out, let her stay.
别进去…　　大家都在里面，我要进去
They're my girls. I'm going back in there.
哈维还好吧？　　他没事了
-Howard. How is he? -Howard's all right.
把电视打开　　　女孩们…
Put the TV on.
我被访问了
Girls, I was interviewed!
讲好了！　　不错嘛！
Looks good.
几乎所有人跟媒体都在外面　　　是电视台…
The media's there.
干嘛？　　电视台记者想访问你…
TV people.
他们在外面
They want to talk to you.
什么事？　　桑尼，我们现正在实况转播
Hello, Sonny. You're on the air.
你介意回答我们几个问题吗？　　不
Would you answer a few questions for us?
你为什么要这么做？
Why are you doing this?
哈？　　你看
Hello?
没事，我看到我自己了，你刚刚问…
I just saw myself there.
我为什么要这么做？　　是的
Why am I doing it?
做什么？　　抢银行
-Doing what? -Robbing a bank.
我不懂你为什么问
I don't know what you mean by that.
我抢银行是因为这里有钱　　　你误会了…
I'm robbing a bank because they got money here.
我是说你为什么想要抢钱？
I mean, why do you feel you have to steal for money?
你不能工作赚钱吗？
Couldn't you get a job?
不行，要做什么？
No. Doing what?
你知道吗？你若要工作，就必须是工会的一员
You know, if you want a job, you got to be a member of a union.
没有工会卡，也没有工作
If you got no union card, you don't get a job.
那不是工会的工作呢？
What about non-union jobs?
他搞不清楚状况啊？
What's wrong with him?
什么叫不是工会的工作？银行出纳员吗？
What do you mean non-union? Like what, a bank teller?
你知道他们一周赚多少？不多，起薪115元，对吧？
You know how much a bank teller makes? Not much.
$115 to start, right?
你要怎么过活？
You can live on that?
我老婆和两个小孩要怎么活？
I got a wife and kids. How am I to live on that? What do you make a week?
你一周赚多少？　　我是来跟你谈有关…
-I'm here to talk to you, Sonny. -Yeah, I'm talking to you.
嗯，我在跟你说话
我们是娱乐，对吧，你有什么好处给我们？
We're entertainment, right? What do you got for us?
你想要好处干嘛？
What do you want to get for it?
你想拿钱…？　　我不想，也不需要，你听着
-Do you expect to be paid? -I don't need to be paid.
我和同伴还有其他9人，我们就快要死了
I'm here with my partner and 9 other people. See, we're dying!
我们就要血溅五步，肝脑涂地
You're going to see our brains on the sidewalk.
你会停播新闻，然后插播这个给妇孺观众看吗？
You'll show that on TV?
Have housewives see that? Instead of "As The World Turns"?
你可以给我什么？总得有些回馈　　　桑尼…
What do you got for me? I want something for that.
你可以放弃　　　放弃？
-You could give up. -Give up?
你去过监狱没？　　没有
-You ever been in prison? -No.
没有？那我们来谈你他妈知道的事吧！
No! Let's talk about something you fucking know about.
你一周赚多少？　　很抱歉通讯突然中断
-How much you make a week? -Transmission has been interrupted.
我们很快会再带您回现场　　　喂？哈？
Please stand by, we will return to our special news cast very soon.
他妈的到底搞什么鬼？喂？
Hello? What the fuck happened?
我想他们不喜欢你的用词
Guess he disliked your language.
去他的，干
Fuck him!
沙尔
他们很可能会跟我们谈判
I don't know, they might deal with us.
外面那个人怎样我不清楚
I don't know about that guy out there.
如果我把调查局扯进来，他们说不定肯谈判
But if I get the FBI involved in this, they might deal.
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
沙尔？　　不行！
你怎么了？　　你不是答应过我什么吗？
What's wrong?
You made a promise, didn't you? Did you promise me something?
你是不是说“不成功，便成仁”
Did you say either we get away clean or we kill ourselves?
你是不是说过？　　我现在不是说那个
-Did you? -I'm not talking about that.
你要不要遵守诺言？我们还做不做？
Do you believe in keeping your promises? Does it still go?
当然　　　那你又在说些什么东西？
Yes.
What are you talking about?
我绝不回监狱
I won't go back to prison.
把他们全杀死，现在！
Kill them all now.
用刺刀把他们全杀死！　　去你的
-Take your bayonet, jam it into their-- -Fuck you!
我们要架飞机，如何？
We ask for a jet. What do you think?
我们要架直升机
We get a helicopter.
叫直升机开到屋顶上
We get a helicopter here, it lands on the roof...
再带我们去坐飞机，我们可以飞离这个国家
...and takes us to a jet. And we fly the fuck out of the country.
沙尔？
我们办得到！
We can do it.
沙尔，沙尔？
我们有王牌，我们根本不知道…
We got them. We don't even know it.
我们有人质
We've got the hostages.
我们从一开始就做错了，我们可以提要求
We've been looking at this the wrong way. We make the demands!
他们一定会给我们要的东西
They'll give us what we want.
我要去热带国家，再也不用忍受下雪天
I'm flying to the tropics. Fuck the snow!
嘿，大嘴巴在哪里？
Where's the mouth?
一起去阿尔及利亚？　　阿尔及利亚？好啊
-You ready to go to Algeria? -Algeria? Yeah, sure!
我们要去气候晴朗的地方！
We're all going to sunny climes!
沙尔，我办得到！
I can make it happen!
我已经撑了这么久，我办得到！
I've made it happen so far.
I can make it happen.
帮我接摩瑞提　　　探长…
Give me Moretti.
所有的人都去打电话吧，打个电话回家报备
All of you, go ahead, make calls. Call home or whatever.
我们要去旅行
We're going on a trip.
是的，桑尼？　　我有话跟你说
I want to talk to you.
我要出来　　　非常好，我会在外面等你
-I'm coming out. -Good, I'll be there.
走吧，他要出来了
Let's go, he's coming out.
现在，你要了解状况
You must understand something.
一旦离开就不能回头
If we leave the country, there's no coming back here.
你知道我说什么吧？不能回头！
There's no coming back.
想要跟谁说话
If there's anyone you want to talk to...
想要跟谁说再见的话，要快
...you want to say goodbye to, do it now.
没有
No.
你有想去的国家吗？
Is there any special country you want to go to?
怀俄明
Wyoming.
那里不行，那不是个国家
No, Wyoming.... That's not a country.
没关系，我来处理
That's all right. I'll take care of it.
放下！听到没？
Put them down!
放下！听到没？看，我什么也没带
Put them down! You hear that? What do I have?
这里也没有，要不要看我的袖子？
See this here, look! I got nothing up my sleeve!
这里也没有，要不要看我的口袋？
I got nothing here either! Want to see my pockets? Here!
你不敢不带枪吧？
You need that gun, right!
摩瑞提，叫他们把枪放下
Moretti! Tell them to put their guns down!
嘿，你！看不懂吗？把枪放回枪袋去！
Put it in your holster!
把枪放下！
Put the guns down!
懂吗？把枪放下！那是什么？
You know what it means to put a gun down? What's this?
那是什么？
谢谢！这就对了！
Right! Thank you very much!
感激万分
你们终于开窍了
You got it, right?
你们终于开窍了，嘿，摩瑞提
You got it, baby! Hey, Moretti!
都是你帮我的
You made it happen!
玛利亚在里面
You got Maria in there!
玛利亚！
他里面有枪！玛利亚…
He's got a gun in there!
玛利亚，玛利亚…
把他带走
Get him the fuck out of here!
老天啊！　　怎么会这样？
How the hell did that happen?
我有沙尔在里面　　　别紧张，别紧张
-I got Sal in there! -Take it easy!
通知管区警察
Notify the precinct.
他是谁？
Who the fuck is that?
只是个西班牙小孩　　　玛利亚又是谁？
One of them Spanish kids.
她被你关…　　沙尔要见桑尼，不然就要开枪了
-Who's Maria? -She's inside.
Sal wants to see Sonny, says he'll shoot unless he does!
他是认真的，桑尼，他是认真的！　　沙尔…
He's serious! Sonny, he means it!
没关系，没关系
It's all right.
没事了
对不起　　　怎么发生的？
-I'm sorry. -How'd that happen?
他女朋友是人质之一，你没事吧
You got his girlfriend in there. You okay?
他想杀我
That fuck tried to kill me.
他打了你好几下　　　我被打了好几下
-You look all squeezed out. -I am squeezed out!
让我看看你的头
Let me see your head, all right?
我在流血！　　让我看看…
-I'm bleeding! -Let me see it.
还好，你想跟我说什么？
It's all right. You want to talk to me about something?
刚有个人打电话来
Should've heard that phone call.
一个疯子打来说，要杀死所有的人
Some creep calls up and says, "Kill everybody. "
每个人都想杀死所有的人
Everyone wants to kill everyone.
这种人到处都会有的，对吧　　　对啊
I think you're going to get assholes like that any how, right?
跟你说…我有个提议
I want to talk to you. I got an offer.
我想要一架直升机
I want a helicopter.
还要可以带我去任何国家的飞机
And a jet to go wherever I want to go.
所以小的不行，要大的那一种
So I don't want a little jet, I want a big one.
有酒吧和钢琴的那种，我很可能会离开国家
One with a bar, a piano. Maybe I want to leave the country.
我不知道直升机是否能来这儿
I don't know whether a helicopter would fit in here or not.
我帮你查查看吧　　　可以停在屋顶上
I'll check it.
不行，上面是柏油，停上去会垮的
-It could land on the roof. -That's asphalt, it'll break through.
让我打电话问我上司好吗？
I'll call my superiors, you understand?
让我…　　那干嘛不叫你上司来呢？
Why not bring your superiors here?
让我直接跟他们谈，就不必透过你了
Why am I talking to you if you got to call superiors?
我们有分歧　　　对，所以我要跟他们说
-We don't always see eye-to-eye. -Yeah, so I'll talk to them.
我会打电话问问他们怎么说
I'll see what they say.
我和他们谈谈，还有其他的要求吗？
I'll talk to them and ask them, all right?
Anything else I can get you?
我要你把我太太带来这儿
I want you to bring my wife down here.
好，那你要给我们什么？　　你要什么？
-What do you give us? -What do you want?
女人质
The women hostages.
老天啊，跟你说话真累
There's no talking to you!
不是说过吗？里面全是女的
I told you, that's all I got in there is women.
你到底要不要谈判啊？
You going to talk to me or what?
你答应我一个要求，我给一个人质
I give one hostage for each thing you give me, see?
给我直升机放一个人质，给我飞机再放一个
The helicopter for a hostage. The jet for a hostage.
带我太太来给你一个，其他人用飞机送回家
You give me my wife, I give you a hostage.
Then the rest come home on the jet.
我看他们能怎么做好吗？
I'll see what they'll do, all right?
在这段期间你赶快选人质
In the meantime, pick out who you want to give us.
还有你太太在哪里？
And tell me where your wife is, all right?
我坐在这儿管我自己的事，我听到桑尼抢银行
I'm here minding my own business, I hear the transistor go "Sonny what?"
我真不敢相信，我抱起孩子就跑
I can 't believe my ears! I grab the kids!
我告诉你那个抢银行的人，绝对不是桑尼
I'm telling you, Sonny didn't do it. It ain't him to rob a bank!
桑尼绝不会伤害，或威胁任何人…
It ain't him to steal or hurt anybody or do nothing wrong!
从我认识他到现在，他从没做过坏事
He's never done wrong since the day I know him!
前天晚上，我们在康尼岛时
Night before last we're at Coney Island. I see he keeps a loaded gun on the car!
发现他买了一把有子弹的枪
我现才知道，他的行为有多么疯狂
Things are adding up how crazy he's acting lately...
都是受坏朋友的影响　　　我就看着他
...and in with a bad crowd. So I look at him.
到床上去，他像疯了似的一直骂小孩
Get in bed. He's yelling at the kids like a madman.
然后他突然叫我带小孩去玩，我不想去
Then he wants me to go in a kiddie ride. I don't want to go.
他就一直吼，乖，宝贝，嘘…
He starts screaming at me.
一直吼个不停
He's screaming and screaming.
在车里我问他，桑尼，你要那把枪干嘛？
I say, "What are you going to do with the gun?"
不会是杀我，把尸体丢到河里吧？
Shoot me and dump me in the river?
我当时好害怕，我从不怕他的
I was scared of him. I never been scared of him.
他妈妈说我们一天到晚打架，还惊动警察
His mother says we always fought. The cops was always at our house.
有一次我在车子里，想用千斤顶打他
I hit him with a jack handle once in the car.
却打到我自己
I didn't even hit him. I hit myself.
全身到处都是瘀伤
You should've seen the bruise on my leg.
他却只穿上衣服戴帽子出门去
He'd put on his hat and coat, he goes out the door.
所以，我不相信是他做的
So they tell me he did it. But I don't believe it.
瓦基克小姐，听我说，你必须到银行来一趟
Mrs. Wortzik, listen to me. They want you down at the bank.
他的身体有可能会做，但他的头脑绝不可能
His body functions might've done it, but he himself, he didn't do it!
亲爱的艾比我梦过掉到水里
"Dear Abby: Lately I've been dreaming about falling into water...
无法接近水面
...and not being able to reach the surface.
我呼吸困难，我惊醒后一身冷汗
I begin to breathe heavily and I wake up in a cold sweat.
一个朋友说我的问题是因为性压抑
A friend tells me that my problem is one of sexual repression. "
玛格莉特，你还好吧？
Margaret, are you all right?
你有没有对里面的女孩做任何事？
Are you doing anything to any of those girls on there?
又是他
He's back again.
这是谁？
Who's this?
桑尼…玛格莉特
Look at Margaret.
她怎么了？
What's the matter with her?
这里没有空气
There's no air in here.
空调坏了吗？
What happened to the air conditioning?
苏，我很抱歉
I'm sorry, Syl.
空调在哪儿？　　地下室
Where's the air conditioning?
In the basement.
沙尔，我下去看看空调
I'll go check the air conditioning.
很快就回来　　　桑尼！
I'll be right back.
干嘛？
我从没坐过飞机
I never been up in an airplane before.
又怎样？
So?
我是说…坐飞机跟坐车一样
I mean, it's safe. It's like a car.
事实上，比车还安全
It's safer than a car.
别害怕，沙尔
It's all right, Sal.
我要去检查空调了
I'm going to go check it now.
沙尔，他们从后面进来了
They're coming in the back!
进去金库，快点
In the vault!
回去，退回去　　　不，不要开枪
-Get back! -No, don't fire!
桑尼，注意点
That's it, Sonny!
带她进去，快进去
Get her in there!
那枪是谁开的？
Who fired that shot?
Pick her up and put her in.
是谁开枪的？
Who fired?
快点，动作快！
Come on! Move!
好，抬腿
Okay, legs!
桑尼！
嘿，桑尼
Get the bullhorn!
拿扩音器给我！
桑尼！
你拿到扩音器了吗？
You got that bullhorn?
嘿，桑尼！
出来吧，桑尼！
Come on out, Sonny!
桑尼！
妈的！这是我“最”需要的了
That's all I need.
桑尼！　　桑尼…
你去处理一下吧！
Take care of that, will you?
桑尼，出来吧！
Come on out!
你们安静点儿行不行啊！
Straighten that out, will you?
桑尼！
桑尼，出来吧！
Sonny, come on out.
桑尼？
桑尼！
桑尼！　　王八蛋，你想害死那些人吗？
You son of a bitch, you want to get those people killed?
出来吧，桑尼！
桑尼，出来吧！
现在就出来吧！
Come on out here, now.
快出来吧！桑尼
桑尼！
快出来吧，桑尼！
我可以看到你了，出来吧
I see you, Sonny, come on!
来吧
你神经错乱啦？
What's the matter with you?
什么？　　你在里面开什么枪啊？
-What? -Why'd you fire that shot in there?
我们有两百五十个警察在这边！　　该死！
We got 250 cops here!
那你们在后头搞什么鬼？　　别再里头乱来！
Fuck you! What were they doing back there?
你到底在玩什么把戏？
What the hell's the matter with you?
什么？　　我们还要不要谈判？
Are we dealing?
他们想进来是不是？　　谁？
-They were trying to get in there? -Who?
少来这套！你心里明白
Come on, you know who!
这到底是怎么回事？　　你们这群蠢蛋
-What's going on? -You're full of shit!
去后面看看发生什么事
Find out what's going on there!
我真的不知道　　　你别装模作样了
-Honest to God, Sonny, I don't know! -Bullshit!
通讯设备还没架好　　　鬼扯…
Communications aren't set up yet.
找其他人来跟我谈吧　　　去你妈的！
Get someone to talk to me!
叫别人来吧，我不想再跟你谈了
I'm not talking to you anymore.
让我跟你谈吧？　　你这说一套做一套的人
-Let me talk to you. -You say this, you do that.
他们在后面做什么？　　我也不知道
Why were they back there?
是吗？你不知道，又在装了　　　那是突击队
I don't know!
You're full of shit!
-It's another force. -A tactical force!
他们喜欢开枪及攀岩走壁
They like to shoot, climb through windows!
没有你的下令，他们也可以蛮干吗？
They like that, right! Without your orders, right?
是的！他们不听我的命令
Yes! Without my orders!
我怎么知道你们不会从屋顶上冲进来？
You coming through the roof?
因为我说不会！　　是吗？你说的全是放屁！
I tell you we won't.
You're telling me a lot of things, but you're not doing them.
我讲了什么？　　他们在干嘛？
What were they doing?!
我不知道　　　你不能回答我
-I don't know! -And you can't answer me.
什么？　　你不能回答我
-You can't answer. -Yes, I can.
我可以，后面再干嘛！　　那告诉我他们在干嘛？
So tell me what they were doing.
我们没有通讯设备，所以我派人到后面去
No communications! I sent someone back there.
若沙尔开杀戒，全都是你的错，不是我的
I got a guy in there who's going to kill somebody. That's your responsibility.
等等，你的要求我们都办好了　　　是吗？
Wait a minute, hold on. We got everything you wanted.
是的，我们找不到直升机，但有辆巴士
Can't get a helicopter, but a bus is coming.
飞机在甘尼迪机场待命，好吗？
We got a jet coming into Kennedy, all right?
可以吗？
好吧？
我们已经找到你太太
We got ahold of your wife.
她现在正要赶过来这里
Your wife is coming.
我们已找到你太太，她现在正要赶过来
We reached her and she's coming here.
可以吗？
Where are you going?
你要去哪？　　不去哪，我还是在这里…
I'm right here. I thought we were going to talk.
我以为我们要谈判的
我也是，但我们还没有谈
I thought so, too. But we're not.
我们现在谈　　　你们却想从后门闯进来
We're trying to get in the back door.
你太太将在三十分钟内赶到这儿
Your wife will be here soon.
可以吗？
满意吗？　　他们为什么枪还指着我？
They're still pointing. They love it.
把枪收好！
Holster that weapon! Holster it!
收好！
把枪收好！
Holster that weapon!
你也是
You too!
好了吧
All right, come on.
怎样？　　你还想怎样？
-What? -What else do you want me to do?
你是要我怎样？
How could you do any better?
我们什么都答应你了
We got all you wanted.
你的要求我都答应
I'll do anything I can to stop anything.
你还需要其他东西吗？
Anything else?
有　　　什么？
-Yeah. -What?
里面的人饿了
I got some people in there that are hungry.
可否给他们点食物？　　没问题，要什么？
-Can you get food? -What do you want?
送些披萨进去，好不好？　　好啊！
-Want some pizzas? -Yeah, all right.
嘿，卡麦
送些披萨进去
Get some pizzas in.
可不可以再来点啤酒？　　嗯…
Can we get some beer, you think?
不好不好，还是汽水吧？
No beer. Let's keep it to soft drinks, all right?
好吧？
卡麦
记得还要有可乐汽水
Some soft drinks too, okay? Cokes!
还要什么吗？　　再来点阿斯匹灵吧！
-What else? -And some aspirin too.
还要阿斯匹灵　　　有人不舒服
Some lady's not feeling well.
没有了吧？
Anything else?
还有…不准耍我！　　不会！我干嘛耍你？
Don't con me.
I'm not! Why would I want to do that?
我已经够烦的了，也不想自找麻烦
I'm in trouble enough as it is. I'm not trying to create any trouble.
好吧！
没事了
It's okay.
直升机没办法停在这儿
They can't bring a helicopter in here.
沙尔，直升机没办法停在这儿
They can't land it here.
他们要换一辆大巴士，可容纳我们全部
They're going to get us a big bus so we can all get in.
接我们去机场
And that's how we get to the airport.
目前情况还不错
It looks good.
还有我刚帮你们叫了些吃的
You people, I just ordered you some food.
也有阿斯匹灵
I even got her some aspirins.
一切都进行得很顺利
So we're moving it along now.
对了！我还得付食物钱，那些做记号的五元钞在哪？
I got to pay for the food. Where's the marked fives?
你刚做了件愚蠢的事
That was a foolish thing you did back there.
愚蠢的事？
Foolish thing.
我们还要继续这样下去？
We going to get the ball rolling?
对啊！不然你以为我在干嘛？
Yeah, what do you think I'm doing?
事情一直在进行
I'm working on it. What's it look like?
你以为这是件简单的事？我不能激怒他们
You think it's easy? I got to keep them cool.
还要顾到你们
I got to keep you people happy.
我想点子又谈判，都是我一人在做
I got to have the ideas and do it all alone.
我在努力了，你想试试吗？
You want to try it?
桑尼，你要的食物来了
Your food is here, Sonny.
我开始讨厌你了
You're starting to get on my nerves.
跟着他进去，不会有事的
Go on with him there. You'll be all right. Go right ahead.
多少钱？　　付过了，已经付过了
-What do I owe you? -It's all paid for.
没关系，我来付　　　有零钱
-No, I've paid for that. -I got it.
拿去
Here.
零钱留着
Keep the change.
你想要这个
You want this?
你们喜欢？
You like it?
摩瑞提，要不要？
Moretti, could you use five?
还有很多
I got a lot for you.
退后，该死的！
Get back, god damn it!
还要…
More! More! More!
可以帮我开门吗？
Could you open it?
谢了
Thank you, man.
我成了明星！
I'm a fucking star!
踢
往上，翻转
抱她起来，她不会有事的
No, just pick her up and hold her. She'll be okay.
你踢得不错嘛！
You kick good. Here.
踢！
往上！
This is where it gets stuck!
就是在这里卡住的
她在愚弄自己
Miriam's making a fool of herself.
谁有烟？　　我有
Anybody got a cigarette? Yeah, I do.
你不是不抽烟？
Sylvia, you don't smoke!
你不抽烟？
You don't?
不抽
那你现在干嘛抽？
Why do you want to start now?
我快吓死了，你不抽烟吗？
-I'm scared to death, that's why. -You don't smoke?
不抽　　　为什么？
No. How come?
我不想得癌症　　　我的天啊！
-I don't want the cancer. -My God!
把烟给我吧
The cigarette.
爱抽就抽吧
Do what you want.
我只觉得应该照顾自己的身体
I think you ought to take care of your body.
我的身体？为什么？
My body? What for?
身体是上帝的庙宇
Your body is the temple of the Lord.
你是认真的？
You're serious!
你可以抢银行
So you rob a bank...
但不能沾恶习，是这样的吗？
...but you keep your body pure. Is that it?
你到底要不要抽？
You going to smoke or what?
要！
Yes.
如果我因此得癌症，你得负一半的责任
If I die of cancer, it'll be half your fault.
不，那是因为你意志力薄弱
No, it's because you're weak.
是的！我意志力薄弱
Right, I'm weak.
你的子弹呢？
Where's your bullets?
我是马维尼…
Mulvaney speaking.
是摩瑞提
It's Moretti.
喂　　　你们千万不要轻举妄动
Will you guys hold it down back there?
桑尼，你太太来了
They're bringing in your wife.
摩瑞提在哪儿？　　可能在酒吧里
-Where's Moretti? -Probably in the bar.
在理发厅里
In the barber shop.
这是什么？
What's that?
我们在你说的地址找到他
We went to Bellevue where you told us...
他说是他太太
...said he was his wife.
在教堂结婚的
They were married in a church.
天啊！
Jesus Christ!
礼昂！
礼昂！在这儿
Leon, over here!
礼昂…
礼昂，我在这边
礼昂！
Happy birthday!
生日快乐！
让让　　　小心他的头…
-Give us some room. -Watch his head!
他是同志？
He's a queer?
探长，他找你
Sarge, he wants you!
我不要这保护罩，拿走！
Get the shield out of here. I don't need it now.
要的时候都不会出现
Where were you 4 hours ago, when I needed it?
他们不会开枪的，桑尼，什么事？
He's not going to shoot. Yeah, Sonny, what?
怎么了？他还好吧？
What happened? Is he all right?
他只是有点头昏罢了
He's a little groggy.
让我跟他说话　　　我等下叫他打电话给你
No, let me talk to him.
I'll get him on his feet and call back.
把门关上
Shut the door!
安静点，我不想听到任何噪音
Stop the noise. I don't want to hear a fucking sound!
打字机！
Typewriter!
挂电话！
Get off the fucking phone.
快点！
Now!
给我些水！
Give me some water.
礼昂
You all right? They give you a shot down at the hospital or something?
你还好吧，礼昂？医院是不是帮你打针了？
我的天啊！
They shot me with, like, unreal!
一针打下去我整个人都昏了
你可要振作点！
You got to get ahold of yourself...
你待会儿还得劝他走出银行
...so you can talk to him, and see if he'll come out.
我不知道
He's got 8 people there, with a Sal. You know him?
里面有八个人，还有个叫沙尔的认识吗？
不太认识　　　他说他要杀死这八个人
-No, not really. -He says he's going to shoot them.
我…帮不上忙的，我不能阻止他
I can't help it. I can't stop him from anything.
他不听你的听谁的？
Who will he listen to, then?
我没办法跟他说，他不会听任何人的话
I can't talk to him. He won't listen to anybody.
他整个夏天都怪怪的
He's been crazy all summer.
六月的时候他就想杀我了
He's tried to kill me since June.
他用枪指着我的头，用刀割我
He put a gun to my head. And he cut me with a knife.
还打我朋友　　　你有试过叫警察吗？
-He beat up my friends. -Did you contact the police?
有什么用？
What good would that do?
他会更生气，他们阻止不了他的
It'd just make him mad. They don't know him. It wouldn't stop him.
总得有人阻止他　　　你不懂，他疯了！
-Somebody's got to stop him. -You don't understand. He's crazy.
他有老婆、小孩
He's got a wife, children.
是个好爸爸
He's a wonderful father.
他的妈妈…
His mother...
你该见识一下，看看他父母，他们简直是场大灾难
...you should see her. Together with his father, they're like a car wreck.
但他挑起重担
It just rolls off his back.
他探望他们，还帮他们付房租…难以置信
He sees them. He pays the rent. Unbelievable!
我是个想结婚的人，他不想，不过…
I was the one that wanted to get married. He didn't really want it...
但他却结婚了，我不知道为什么！
...but he did it. I don't know why.
你为什么想结婚？
Why did you want to get married?
我以为会对我有好处
I thought it would help me.
可是…
可是…实际上没有
But it didn't.
我以前很困惑…
I was so confused. I was doing...
常常做傻事
...insane things.
比方说？
What sort of things, Leon?
我在婚礼后
After the wedding...
逃去大西洋城十天
...I ran off for 10 days to Atlantic City.
桑尼气疯了
Sonny was frantic.
他知道我喝了酒，但不知道我跟谁去了哪
He knew I'd been drinking. He didn't know where I was, who I was with.
我无法解释我所做过的事
I couldn't explain the things I did.
后来我去看心理医生
So I went to a psychiatrist...
他说…
...who told me...
我是个被困在男人身体的女人
...that I was a woman trapped in a man's body.
所以一听到消息，桑尼便想帮我钱做变性手术
So right away he wanted to give me money for the sex change operation.
但是他要去哪儿钱呢？
But where was he going to get it?
两千伍百元？
$2,500?
他本来就已经债台高筑了
My God, he was in hock up to his ears already.
他需要钱好让你做变性手术？
He needed the money for your operation?
他为这件事非常烦恼
It drove him crazy.
他因此常常无故发脾气
He would fly into these rages.
我也变得很沮丧
And I got more depressed than ever.
因为我知道，我永远不可能动手术
I knew I'd never get my operation.
所以…
我企图自杀，我吞下的药，数都数不清
So I tried to kill myself. I took about a half a pound of pills.
蓝的、红的、黄的，所有的药我几乎都试过了
Blues, yellows, screamers, uppers, downers, you name it.
后来我被送进医院
And I wound up in the hospital.
桑尼来看我时
And Sonny comes there...
他看着我
...and he just looks at me.
问我
And he says...
礼昂，为什么？
..."Why, Leon?
现在不是很好吗？
When things were going so good?"
你不觉得…
Don't you think...
他是因为你才抢银行的？
...he did it for you?
嗯，我想是吧
Yeah, I guess so.
难道你不想阻止他犯下大错？
Don't you think you owe it to him to try to get him out?
我不敢跟他说话
I can't talk to him.
礼昂，你脱不了关系，你是个共犯
You're up to your neck in it. You're an accessory.
这件事不能怪我　　　等等，你可以帮我们
-They can't hold me responsible. -Wait, you could help us a little.
我很怕
I'm afraid.
只要跟他说话，他在电话上又不能伤害你
Just talk to him for a minute. How can he hurt you on the phone?
我不能…我不知道要说什么
I can't. I don't know what to....
跟他讲几句就行了
Just talk with him on the phone.
你考虑看看
You think about it.
他不想跟你说话
He won't talk to you.
你什么意思？
What do you mean he won't talk to me?
我再去试试看
I'll work on it.
你不是已经在劝他了吗？
I thought you were doing that.
他不想跟我说话
He won't talk to me.
警方正在询问礼昂谢摩，自认是双性恋的26岁男子
They are questioning Leon Schermer, a 26-year-old admitted homosexual...
声称曾与嫌犯于11月在教堂结过婚
...who claims to have married one of the bank robbers last November.
根据我们在理发厅的消息来源指出
According to sources on the barber shop where Leon is held...
礼昂的婚礼
...Leon has reportedly said...
是由牧师柏克所主持的
...they were married in an official ceremony by a Father Burke.
礼昂的话已经过证实
Leon 's story has been confirmed.
7个男的伴娘，还有桑尼的妈和七十个客人
7 bridesmaids, all male, Sonny's mother and 70 other guests...
所有的同性恋团体都出席了
...all members of the gay community.
我们已经取得一张礼昂穿婚纱礼服的照片
We've been able to obtain a still photograph of Leon on his gown.
礼昂还透露
Leon has confirmed...
所有的礼服共花了七百多元
...that the gowns for himself and his bridesmaids cost $700.
我们至今仍无法与该牧师连系
We have not confirmed the story...
但据说他已被教会免职
...with the priest. But we are told that he was subsequently defrocked.
全国各地的同性恋已陆续打电话进来
Phone calls have arrived from various factions of the gay community.
有人支持桑尼的行动，也有人谴责
Some on support of Sonny and his actions, others condemning...
认为这件抢案和这种婚姻
...the present events and calling the marriage...
是“全然的表现欲”
...a farce, and, quote, "A case of sheer exhibitionism. " End quote.
我们正在报导两名同性恋以人质做威胁
Coverage of the robbery where 2 homosexuals hold hostages...
要求坐直升机与飞机离开国家　　　桑尼…
...for their demands of a helicopter, a jet....
桑尼…电视上说银行里有两个同性恋，听到没？
They said, "2 homosexuals in the bank. " Right on TV! You hear?
那又怎样？他们爱怎么说就怎么说
What difference does it make? They can say anything they want.
随他们去说吧！
Let them say it.
但我不是个同性恋
I'm not homosexual.
叫他们搞清楚，这会在电视上播出的
Tell them to get that right. That's going out on the TV.
沙尔，你要我怎么做？我管不了播出内容
What am I supposed to do? I can't control what they say on television.
你要我怎么做，我已尽全力，我管不了他们
What should I do? I'm doing everything I can, I can't do that.
沙尔
放心吧，他们像看戏很快就会忘的，无所谓
Forget about it. It's just a freak show to them, anyway. It don't matter.
他们怎么说都无所谓
Whatever they say don't matter.
没事的
It'll be all right.
你怎么了？
What's the matter with you?
你怎么可以让这小事坏兴致？
You shouldn't let something like that spoil your fun.
看开点
You have to get fun out of life.
为什么飞机还不来？
Where's the god damn jet?
不需要飞机时
They're always screaming overhead, going somewhere...
它们总是从天上呼啸而过
...when you don't need them, you know?
你上飞机后，要跟驾驶员说什么？
What are you going to tell the pilot when you get on the plane?
这是应该知道的事情
You have to know, right?
荷兰其实是个不错的国家
Holland's pretty good.
荷兰？怎么说？　　他们在战争时很照顾难民
-Holland? -They sheltered people during the war.
是个不错的民族
They're good people.
荷兰在哪儿？
Where's Holland?
荷兰在…
It's right up....
在这儿！
It's over there!
可不可以给我地图？
快进金库，快点！
Get in the vault. Come on!
Quickly!
他们在等我们采取行动
They're waiting for us to do something, I think.
桑尼…
桑尼，快出来！
Come on out for a second.
是他！就是他！
It's him.
出来！我有话跟你说
Come on out. I want to talk to you a second.
去吧！桑尼　　　桑尼
Come on!
桑尼！
桑尼！出来一下
Come on out, Sonny.
桑尼？
出来一下
Come on out a minute.
出来！
That's it.
摩瑞提！
又怎么了？把灯打开
What the fuck is going on? Get the lights back on.
摩瑞提！
你是谁？
Who are you?
调查局的沙登
FBI, Sheldon.
很好
Good.
终于有人出面了，我们可以办正事了吧？
About time. Maybe we can get this thing started?
听好，把灯打开…
Look, get the lights back on...
还有空调，我们里面没有空调了
...and the air conditioner. We got no air conditioning.
桑尼，我们不会给你面子了
No more favors. That's all over.
给我面子？
Favors?
你今晚都是在给我面子？
You been doing me favors all night?
飞机准备好了，礼车半小时后就到
I have a jet, limo will be here in a half hour.
但是我要人质
I want the hostages.
少来，别唬我！
No, no. Bullshit!
我想合作，不是作对　　　人质是我的护身符
I'd like to work with you on this, not against you.
The hostages are what's keeping me alive.
什么时候放他们出来？
When do I get them?
没有人告诉你吗？
Didn't they tell you?
我要听你亲口说
I'd like to hear it from you.
一辆车，换一个人质
You get one hostage for the limousine that you bring me in.
一架飞机，换一个人质
One hostage for the jet.
到了机场，上了飞机，等我检查好
Then I get to the airport. I go into the plane, check it out.
如果一切无误，我就会放了剩下的人质
And if it's okay, they all come out.
我要进去　　　为什么？
-I want to go inside. -Why?
确认大家都安全
See if everybody's all right.
他们很安全
They're all right.
我要亲眼目睹
No, I have to see.
你有种！
You got guts.
若我们杀了他们，还会让你活着出来吗？
Think if we slit their throats, we're going to let you out?
我要亲眼看到
I have to see.
我得跟我同伴商量
I got to check with my partner.
沙尔，调查局的人要进来
The FBI, Sal. They're coming in.
你想杀我？
You'd like to kill me?
你一定很想杀了我
Bet you would.
我不想杀你
I wouldn't like to kill you.
但必要时我会的
I will if I have to.
这是你的工作，对吧？
It's your job, right?
我希望杀我的人
The guy who kills me...
是因为恨我入骨，而不是因为工作因素
...I hope he does it because he hates my guts, not because it's his job.
不要报上真名，他是调查局的人
Nobody give your right name. It's the FBI.
只想确定各位小姐没有受伤
Just want to make sure all you young ladies are all right in here.
他们很久前就要了飞机，你们究竟在拖什么？
They asked for the jet hours ago. What are you doing?
我们正在安排，两小时后就救你们出去
That's being set up. We'll have you out in a few hours.
两小时后？　　为什么不直接答应他们的要求？
-A few hours? -Why don't you give them what they want?
他们会得到想要的，我们也要确定能得到所要的
They'll get it. We want to be sure we get what we want.
我要将你们平安带离这里
Let's get you all out of here safe.
也包括你们俩
You two boys too.
不要再靠近了
That's close enough.
去告诉电视台，别再播银行里有两个同性恋
Tell the TV to stop saying there's 2 homosexuals in here.
我会的，沙尔
I will.
桑尼，出来一下
Outside for a minute, Sonny?
你处理得很好
You handled yourself well.
比一般人还好，减少可能会有的伤亡人数
A lot of men would have choked. We might have had a death on our hands.
你处理得很好，我尊敬你
But you handled it. I respect that.
把沙尔交给我们来处理
Don't you try to take Sal. We'll handle him.
你只要不轻举妄动，就不会受伤
Sit tight and you won't get hurt.
等一下，你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你不必管
You just sit quiet.
把沙尔交给我们处理吧！
We'll handle Sal.
你以为我会出卖他？去你妈的！
You think I'd sell him out, you fuck?
他说什么？
What'd he say?
他只是告诉我他们的计划
He was just talking about arrangements.
我有告诉他电视的事，别担心
I talked to him about the TV. It will be all right.
就这样？　　对
That's all?
那他为什么不在这儿说？
Why couldn't he say it here?
我不知道！他想给我看车子要打哪儿进来
I don't know. He wanted to show me how the bus is going to come in.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
去倒杯水！
Someone get a glass of water.
有没有手帕？
Got a hankie?
他们在披萨里下毒！
They poisoned the pizza.
不是啦！
It's not the pizza!
他有糖尿病！
He's got diabetes.
他刚有喝可乐，别给他吃东西，我来拿
He had some Coke before. Don't give him anything. I'll hold it.
需要我们帮忙吗，马维尼先生？
What can we do for you, Mr. Mulvaney? Tell us.
这里有没有医生？
Is there a doctor out here?
我们需要一个医生
We need a doctor in here.
We need a doctor.
怎么了？　　经理有糖尿病
What?
他不太舒服
The manager, he's diabetic. He don't look good.
我要搜身
I got to search you.
只准他进来
Just him.
桑尼
我已经说服礼昂跟你说话，他现在在电话上
I've convinced Leon to talk to you. He's on the phone now.
他要接了
He's coming on.
喂？
喂？礼昂？
Hello, Leon?
喂？
Hello, Sonny.
喂？桑尼
怎么了？
What happened?
你…还好吧？
How are you doing?
嗯，我出院了
Well, I'm out of the hospital.
我知道，我以为你永远也不能出院
Yeah, I know. I thought you'd never get out.
我没想过会是这样出院的　　　是啊
I never thought I'd get out this way, I'll tell you.
你还好吧？
How are you doing?
我在发抖　　　是吗？
I'm a little shaky.
摩瑞提说你不想跟我说话
Moretti told me that you were all drugged up...
我想可能是你吃药的关系
...so I figured that's why you didn't want to talk. I was wondering why.
我刚还在想为什么你不想跟我说话
对啊，那里好糟糕
It was really terrible, you know?
一进去他们就认定你疯了
You walk in, and right away they say you're crazy.
然后就开始帮你打针，我的意思是…
Then they start sticking things in your arm.
你一天到晚昏昏沉沉，病怎么好得起来？
How do they expect you to get uncrazy if you're asleep all the time?
我才刚刚开始清醒
I'm just starting to come out of it now.
嗯　　　嗯
So, how are you?
你好吗？　　我很好
I'm fine.
这个场面有点扯吧？
This is something, huh?
是啊…
我不知道礼昂…我就快死在这儿了
I don't know. I'm dying here.
我快死了
听听你自己说“快死了”的德性？
You ever listen to yourself when you say, "You're dying"?
你听听你自己！　　你在说什么？
-You ever listen to yourself? -What are you talking about?
你这话是什么意思？什么你快死了
What do you mean, what am I talking about? "You're dying. "
你知道你每天都跟我说，你快死了吗？
Do you know that you say that to me every day?
不是你快死了，是你在杀死你身边的人
You're not dying. You're killing the people around you.
礼昂，别这样好不好？不要跟我废话
Leon, don't give me that shit. I don't need that deep shit now!
我想你可能不知道，这话是什么意思
You don't realize what the things you do mean.
是吗？我很清楚
Yeah?
I know what I do.
你用枪指着别人的头
You stock a gun to somebody's head.
我有时不知道自己在做什么　　　对
I don't know what I'm doing sometimes.
很明显的你不知道
Obviously, you don't.
“睡吧，礼昂，这样我扣扳机时就不会痛”
"Go to sleep so it won't hurt when I shoot. "
你以为我在医院里做啥？
What do you think I've been doing on the hospital?
我吃药是为了离开你，对吧？　　是啊
I take a handful of pills to get away from you.
结果我现在又和你通电话
Now I'm talking to you on the phone again.
我没有工作，没有朋友
I've got no job. I don't have friends.
我必须要跟人接触才活得下去
I can't live. I have to live with people.
对不起，你老是把死挂在嘴边，我听不下去了
This death business, I'm sorry.
我不知道我为什么要在这忍受你这堆废话
I don't know what I'm getting here with that shit.
你要我怎么回答？事情已经发生了
What am I supposed to say to that? This is going on.
你居然说这种话　　　对不起！
-You're giving me that shit. -I'm sorry.
你知道我现在的处境
You know what's happening.
你该知道我受的压力很大，你知道的！
You know the pressures I've been having, right?
你知道我的这些压力…你在医院里…
I got these pressures. You know it. You're in that hospital...
全身插满了管子，又想动变性手术，对吧？
...with them tubes coming out and want that operation, right?
你跟我说了一堆废话，大家都给我气受
You're giving me that shit. Everybody's giving me shit.
每个人都要钱，你要我就帮你　　　对
Everybody needs money. So you needed money? I got you money.
可是我没叫你去抢银行啊
I didn't ask you to rob a bank!
我知道你没要我去…
I know you didn't ask me.
我并不怪任何人
I'm not putting this on anybody, you know?
我不怪任何人，因为我是出于自愿的
Nothing on nobody! I did this on my own. You see?
你搞清楚了吗？我只是想让你知道…
All on my own, I did it. But I want you to know something.
我绝对能逃得出去
I want you to know that I'm getting out of here.
我会坐飞机离开这个地方
I'm getting a plane out of here...
我只是想让你知道而已，我要你来这儿…
...and I just wanted you to know it. And I wanted you to come down...
只是…想跟你说拜拜
...and I wanted to just say goodbye to you.
或是你也可以跟我一起走
Or, if you wanted to, you could come with me.
你可以自己决定，这就是我想讲的了
You're free to do what you want. That's what...
...I wanted to say to you.
我可以自己决定？　　对
-I'm free to do what I want? -Right.
我花了6个月时间试着离开你
I try to get away from you for months and I'm going with you on a trip?
现在却要我跟你一起离开？
你要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
我还不知道，之前是说去阿尔及利亚
I don't know where yet. We said Algeria. I don't know.
可能是去阿尔及利亚吧
So I'll go to Algeria. I don't know yet.
为什么选阿尔及利亚？
Why are you going to Algeria?
我不知道，那里有一家强森饭店
I don't know why. They got a Howard Johnson's there.
你疯了，知道吗？你真的疯了！
You're warped, you know that? You're really warped.
我真的疯了！我知道
I'm warped. I know I'm warped.
天啊！阿尔及利亚…
Algeria!
他们带着面具走路，头上又有怪东西
You know they walk around with masks on, things on their heads.
那边都是些疯子　　　那我该怎么办？
-They're a bunch of crazy people. -What am I supposed to do?
你可以选个好一点的地方　　　哪儿？
-You could have picked a better place. -Like where?
瑞士还是丹麦？
Sweden? Denmark?
对啊，那里不错
Yeah, like that.
沙尔想去怀俄明州
You know what? Sal wanted to go to Wyoming.
天啊！那不是个国家，他不知道怀俄明在哪
I had to tell him it's not a country. He don't know where Wyoming is.
我和不知怀俄明在哪的人一起打劫
I'm with a guy who don't know where Wyoming is. Think you got problems?
有问题的人不只是你！
那么…沙尔跟你一起
So, Sal is with you?
喔我的天！
Oh, boy!
我看你们还是投降得好
You'd be better off giving up.
我不会投降的，不然我何苦做这一切？
I'm not giving up, because why have I done this so far?
事情已经做到这个地步，现在何必投降？
I've gone so far with this, and why should I give up now?
我怎么能投降？
I can't give up.
你可以帮我个忙吗？　　什么忙？
-Would you do me a favor? -Yeah, what?
带我来这里的人
These guys that have me down here...
他们认为我是同谋
...they think I'm part of the plot to rob the bank.
怎么可能？太疯狂了
That's crazy, Leon. That's crazy. They're bullshitting you.
他们在唬你，想要耍你
They're giving you a snow job.
他们的确说我是共犯　　　才不是…
They told me I was an accessory.
他们胡说八道，别相信
That's just a con job on you. Don't listen to that.
我一定得听他们的…我在监狱里会活不下去
I have to listen to it. I can't survive in prison, Sonny.
礼昂，你不可能会坐牢的　　　你怎么知道？
-You're not going to prison. -How do you know?
我就是知道，你不会坐牢的
Because I know. Believe me.
拜托…告诉他们　　　拜托什么？
Look, please, just tell them.
告诉他们什么？
Tell them what?
告诉他们你我不是一伙的？
That you didn't do it?
他们现在在听电话吗？
Are they on the phone now?
对
Yeah.
好极了！礼昂，真是好极了
That's great, Leon. That's really terrific.
你跟我通话，还让他们监听，你可真聪明
You talk with them on the phone. Really smart!
我是被逼的　　　什么意思？
-I have no choice! -What do you mean?
你要我怎么办？我身边有七万多个警察围着
What am I supposed to do? There are 7,000 fucking cops all around me.
谁在听电话？　　不要怪在我头上
-Who's on now? -Don't lay it on me!
我没有怪你！可你知道他们在搞鬼吧？
I'm not, but you knew that was going on, right?
讲什么我怪你，你一定知发生什么事
You knew what was happening, right?
没错…可是我…
Yeah!
我只想知道谁在听电话？
I want to know who's on the phone now.
摩瑞提？摩瑞提，是你吗？
Moretti, is that you?
喂？
总有人说说话啊，他们还在听吗？
Will somebody talk to me? Somebody going to talk to me or what?
他们还在听吗？
They on now?
他们不会跟你说话的
They won't talk to you.
好吧，他没参与这次的计划
He didn't do it, okay? He had nothing to do with it.
他跟这件事一点关系都没有
可以了吧？
Will you get off the phone?
你们可以挂了吧？他们挂了吗？
Are they off?
嗯
That really convinced them. They wanted to know. Did I do it for you?
他们应该相信你了吧
这是他们要知道的，我帮你洗清罪名
谢谢你
Yeah, thanks. Thank you very much.
你现在要怎么办？
So now what? What are you going to do?
我想…
I thought...
我想我会回去医院
...that I would go back to the hospital.
他们人很好，也有心要帮我
They're really nice there. They seem like they're trying to help me.
你已经找到你要的东西了
That's good, then. You found something.
我也不太确定
I don't know if I have or not.
所以…你还是会去动手术吧？
Are you still going to have the operation?
会呀，当然会
Yeah!
我还应该跟你说什么？
So then, what am I supposed to say to you?
谢谢你
Thanks a lot...
还有…祝你一路顺风
...and bon voyage.
有缘再见面　　　是啊
Yeah, right. See you sometime.
我会在梦里见到你的
I'll see you in my dreams.
我会写首歌的
Right, I'll write a song.
知道吗…人生有时真有趣　　　你说过很多次了
-I don't know. Life's so funny. -You said a mouthful, sweetheart.
那…拜拜了
Goodbye, huh?
哈　　　可不可以给我…
Give me.... Can I have--
你们把银行电话全掐了，能否给我一支分线？
You cut off the incoming calls. Can I have a line?
我要打电话给我老婆跟小孩
I want to talk to my wife and to my kids.
他要一支可以打出去的电话
He wants an outside line, is it all right?
给我接另一条线
I want a line.
好，我马上处理
I'm getting it.
你知道吗？我可以打电话给任何人
I could call anybody, they'd put them on the phone.
教宗、太空人…
The Pope, an astronaut...
智者中的智者
...the wisest of the wise.
结果我居然得打给那个女人
Who do I have to call?
我不知道该怎么办？
I just don't know what to do.
喂？　　嘿，安祺
Angie.
桑尼，天啊，我看到新闻了
Jesus! I was watching it on TV.
小孩在哪？　　他们还不知道我叫他们去邻居家
-Where are the kids? -I sent them to the neighbors.
桑尼，我真的不敢相信…这不像你啊
I can't believe! I mean, it ain't like you.
我知道
I know.
你从来不会这样的，你从没伤害过任何人
You've never done anything like it before on your life.
你知道吗？我快死了，我快死在这里了
I'm dying, you know that? I'm dying here.
桑尼，我一直怪自己，我知道你最近一直心神不宁
I blame myself. I notice you been tense, like something is happening.
你前天像疯了似的骂小孩
Like that night you're yelling at the kids like a madman.
还叫我去
Then you want me to go...
坐小孩的云霄飞车
...on that ride, here to there, full of those kids.
这太疯狂了，我不想去
It's ridiculous. I'm not about to go, so you yell at me...
你还骂我，逼我上去
..."You pig, get on the fucking ride! " Everything fell out of me.
我的心都碎了，整个人都崩溃了
My heart, my liver, just fell to the floor. Everything!
你知道我的感受吗？你当着这么多人骂我
You know what it felt like? You yelling at me in front of all those people?
因为你从来也没这样对我过
You never talked to me like that before.
我以为你会杀了我，然后把尸体丢到河里
I think, "He's going to shoot me and dump my body in the river. "
安祺，闭嘴　　　我是说我好怕你…
I was scared of you!
我怕死你了…　　你给我闭嘴，听我说…
Will you shut the fuck up and listen to me? Just listen to me!
你看，又是这样，满口的脏话
You see that? With the language?
我是想跟你说话，但你…
I'm trying to talk to you, and you--
我想我无法跟你说话！
A person can't communicate with you!
你把我当成什么？我是你老婆…
What am I here? I'm your wife. I'm your wife!
你伤了我，你知道吗？
You know something? You hurt me.
你伤透我了，你竟跑去与男人结婚？
You hurt me, you know that? Can you imagine, marrying another man?
我做错了什么？
Did I ever do anything to make you do that?
我有拒绝过你吗？
Did I ever turn you down or anything?
我只不过肥了点
I know I let myself get fat.
别说你胖，别这么说　　　你无法忍受我肥胖
-Don't call yourself fat. -You can't stand me to say it.
就像我无法忍受你抢银行，桑尼，这才是爱！
Like I can't stand you being a bank robber. That's what love is.
喔，你知道什么是爱？
Yeah? You know what love is?
既然你这么清楚，为什么不过来？
If you know what love is so much, why didn't you come down here?
跟我谈爱，再说啊
Talk to me about love, go ahead.
桑尼，我好害怕…
Sonny, I'm scared.
我好害怕…他们会不会枪毙我？
I'm scared. Are they going to shoot me or something?
他们才不会枪毙你
No, they're not!
你该看电视，他们有大跑、冲锋枪，样样俱全
You should see it on the TV. They got cannons, machine guns.
他们要抓的是我不是你
They're after me, Angie, not you.
我好晚才知道你和沙尔出事了
It's late already by the time I find out...
我找不到保母，怎么去见你？
...it's just you and Sal. I can't get a babysitter! What'll I do?
听着
我必须带他回去检查心脏
I think I better take him back for a cardiac check.
他怎么了？会死吗？　　不是不是…
What's the matter? He going to die or what?
只是要预防一下，这儿太暖了
It's just a precautionary measure. It's awfully warm in here.
好吧，带他出去
All right, then. Let's go, let him out.
我不去，我还好
I'm not going. I'm okay.
帮我打针就好
I just needed the injection.
你干嘛？想逞英雄？你看起来不太好，还是出去吧
You trying to be a hero? You don't look good. We'll let you out.
我不是逞强
I'm not trying to be anything.
我只想自己一个人，可以吗？
I just want to be left alone.
没人吵你啊　　　我希望你从没进过这间银行
-No one is bothering you. -I wish to fuck you never came!
就这样
That's all.
你不用假惺惺装好人
Don't try to act like you're an angel of human kindness.
出柜上街头！出柜上街头！
Out of the closet and into the streets!
出柜上街头！…
桑尼万岁！…
Sonny all the way! Sonny all the way!
女士们
Ladies!
请原谅我刚刚用的字眼
I want to apologize for my use of language back there.
为什么？你刚说了什么？
Why? What did you say?
他说了什么？　　他骂脏话
What?
He said the 'F' word.
啊？　　他说什么？
What did he say?
他骂脏话
He said the 'F' word.
可恶！　　我知道，玛莉安
-Fuck. -I know, Miriam!
我是基督教徒，不能听这些字眼
I'm a Christian and my ears are not garbage cans.
别这样嘛…
我们不要管他们了　　　那就别管他们了
-Then we shouldn't go after them. -Then we won't.
怎么了？　　桑尼…
What's that?
桑尼，你可否出来一下？
Could you come out, please?
是我妈
My mother.
桑尼
有人来看你了，桑尼？
Someone here to see you.
可否出来一下？
Could you come out, please?
桑尼
桑尼，出来一下
Sonny, could you come out, please?
你们看到那女人吗？
妈，你来干嘛？
Mom, what are you doing down here?
我不要你在这儿　　　喔，桑尼…
I don't need you down here.
布鲁克林的人都在这，还有三家电视台采访
All of Brooklyn is out here. Three networks of television.
我知道怎么做，别担心　　　我刚跟FBI谈过…
-I got it all worked out, Ma. -I talked to the man from the FBI.
你跟谁谈过？不要跟任何人讲话　　　他说…
Who? No, don't talk to anybody.
他说你要是现在出来，就会没事了
He says if you come out now, everything is going to be all right.
我只是想帮你　　　不要跟调查局的人说话
-I'm trying to get you out of this. -Don't talk to the FBI.
我全告诉他们了
I told them everything...
包括你在越战的事，还有你以前工作表现一向很好
...how you were in the war in Vietnam, I told them you always had good jobs.
我还说你64年和高华德参加党大会…
I told them you were with Goldwater in '64 in the convention and--
妈，听我说，我就要坐飞机去阿尔及利亚
Listen, I'm getting a plane and I'm going to Algeria.
我会写信给你的　　　阿尔及利亚？
I'll write you from there.
我必须离开这里　　　真搞不懂你
-I've got to go! -I don't understand you.
如果我留在里跟你间聊
If I stay and talk to you, they won't send the limousine.
他们就不会派车子载我们去机场
他们会以为我要投降　　　投降又会怎么样？
-They'll think I'll come out with you. -What's the matter with that?
调查局的人什么都了解，他们知道不是你的错…
Because I'm not coming with you.
The FBI understands everything, that it is not you that is doing this.
他们知道你是因为家里的压力大
It's the pressures from your home life!
别把安祺扯进来…　　我有说她的坏话吗？
-Don't get on Angie now. -Did I say one word against her?
你的人生　　　安祺没有错，是我错
You were going to. She has nothing to do with it, it's me!
本来你的人生是美好的
Your life was sweetness and roses.
要不是安祺你也不会跟礼昂在一起，这你也知道
You wouldn't need Leon if Angie was treating you right, you know that!
我不懂你为什么要跟她在一起
I don't understand why you want to sleep with her anyway.
你有两个小孩在领福利金
You got 2 kids on welfare now.
难不成你想跟她再生一个？
-You want 3 kids on welfare? -I can't talk to you about this now.
妈，现在不是谈这个的时候
妈，拜托…　　你现在要怎么办？出来啊！出来
What are you going to do? Come out.
我不能出来，我不能，沙尔和人质都在里面
I can't come out. I can't.
Sal is in there with the people.
要是我出来，沙尔会杀了他们的　　　老天啊
If I come out, he's going to kill them.
跑！跑！　　跑？
Run!
跑！　　我能跑去哪儿？我不能跑
Run? Where am I going to run? Ma, I can't run!
或许…我想应该…　　我跑不了的，妈，拜托
-Maybe-- -There's no maybe. No maybes.
妈，求求你回家，爸呢？他没有来这儿吧？
You got to go home. Where's Pop? He didn't come, did he?
没，他在生你气，他说他没有你这种儿子！
Is he pissed off at you! He says he doesn't have a son.
他说你已经死了　　　他是对的
-He says you're dead. -He's right.
我是个没用的边缘人
I'm a fuck-up and an outcast and that's it.
接近我的人都会倒霉
You come near me, you're going to get fucked over and fucked out!
我必须要走了，麻烦带她回家，好吗？
Now, I got to go, Ma. Get her home, okay?
带她回家
Just take her home.
你知道你小时候有多可爱吗？
How beautiful you were when you were a baby!
现在就回家去！带她回去！
Get her home now!
（十分钟）
Ten minutes.
我在身心
Being of sound mind...
健全的状况下…
...and body....
你知道怎么写吧？
You know what they....
给我亲爱的太太
To my darling wife...
礼昂
...Leon...
我爱你…
...whom I love...
世界上
...more than any man...
无人能比
...has loved another man...
直到永远…
...in all eternity.
我留下了…
I leave...
两千七百元
...$2,700...
是从我的寿险理赔金里拿出来的
...from my $10,000 life insurance policy...
就当做…
...to be used...
你的变性手术费用
...for your sex change operation.
如果有剩…
If there is any money left over...
全都给你
...I want it to go to you...
在我的…
...at my first...
我的一周年忌日
...at the first anniversary of my death...
别忘了来看我
...at my grave.
给我的老婆…
To my wife...
亲爱的老婆
...to my sweet wife...
安祺
...Angela...
我理赔金中的五千元是要给你的
...$5,000 from the same policy.
你是我唯一
You are the only woman...
爱过的女人
...that I ever loved.
我在此令人鼻酸的一刻
And I repledge my love to you...
重申对你的爱
...in this sad moment.
给金咪
To little Kimmy...
与提米
...and Timmy.
提米，希望你能记得我
I hope you remember me, Timmy.
你现在是这个家里的男人了
You're the little man of the family now...
希望你能代我照顾这个家
...and I hope you look after them for me.
我亲爱的妈妈
To my mother...
原谅我
...I ask forgiveness.
你无法了解…
You don't understand...
我的言语
...the things I said...
和行为
...and did.
我就是我，我与众不同
But I'm me and I'm different.
我希望能有个军队仪式葬礼
I want a military funeral...
我有权要求免费下葬
...and I'm entitled to have one, free of charge.
愿上帝保佑你
God bless you...
看顾你…
...and watch over you...
直到我们再相会
...till we are joined in the hereafter.
我来签名
Here, I'll sign. I'll spell that last name.
小心
Watch out!
小心…
别这样嘛！探长，一张照片就好
Come on, Sarge, just one picture?
退后！退后！
Back, back!
你是司机？　　是的
You the driver?
我想检查一下
I want to check it out.
这椅子可以拿下来？　　不行，固定住了
Seats come out?
They're bolted.
好吧！灯从那边照过来
All right, here. Light me on that side.
照那边
Over there.
啊，你就是那个男的
You're the man, huh?
我刚看到报导
I was watching. I saw you, man!
你应该看看，你不会相信
You should see yourself, you wouldn't believe it!
我相信
I believe it.
但是席拉绝不会相信的
Sheila won't!
谁是席拉？　　我妈
-Who? -My old lady!
他们打电话来，叫我到公园西路258号
They said, "Gas up a stretch, go to 285 Prospect Park West. "
灯光照过来点
Give me some light over here.
我以为又是一堆…从按摩院出来的客人
I said, "Shit, another load from the massage parlors! "
没问题了
It's okay.
我一定会记得你
I'm going to remember you.
这是墨飞探员，他来开车
This is Agent Murphy. He'll be your driver.
不，我要他
No, I want him.
我要这个黑人　　　我才不要这浑水
-Give me the black guy. -I'm not into that shit.
别这样，没人会伤害你的
Nobody will hurt you.
没有人会被杀，要杀早杀了，还等现在？
If they were going to shoot, they would've shot already.
我不答应　　　你不答应？
-I can't allow that, Sonny. -You can't allow?
你谁啊？这里我下命令
What makes you think you can say shit to me? I'm running this.
我会付钱的，你要多少，一百元？
I'll pay you. What do you want? $100? $200?
两百元？一千元？怎样？
$1,000? Come on.
别看他，我才是老大
Don't look at him, I'm running this.
来嘛！
会很好玩喔
Look, it'll be an adventure.
要杀杀白人，别杀我
You men that shoot, aim for white meat.
你走吧
Take a walk.
我要他
Give me him.
你以为你在跟白痴谈判啊？
Think I'm an idiot?
滚，条子！
Take a walk, cop!
大家都想耍老千
Everybody is a con man.
我要所有人都到对面去
I want everyone across the street.
退到对面去
I want them all back, on the sidewalk!
快呀
Let's go!
至少我知道我面对的人是谁
At least I know who I'm dealing with now.
这支笔给你
Here's a pen for you. Come on!
站在这儿别动
Don't move, okay?
桑尼，你的文件
Here's your document.
谢谢　　　你必须签名
-Thanks. -You've got to sign it!
准备走了
We're taking off.
我们要走了
We're going now.
沙尔，他在哪儿？沙尔…
Sal! Where is he?
沙尔
就这样，我们要上路了
That's it, we're going.
各位，要上路了
Here, people, let's go! We're going.
我可以拿我的毛衣吗？　　拿你该拿的
-Can I get my sweater? -Get what you had when you came in.
沙尔
你还好吧？
How are you doing?
还好　　　还好？
Good.
我们要上路了，好吗？
We're going to do it, right?
我们要上路了，沙尔，你看
We're going to do it.
注意看着他，他是司机
You got to keep your eye on him. He's the driver.
我需要这把枪　　　不，这是我的
-I need it. -No, it's mine.
你要看好这小子
You got to keep your eye on him, see?
现在怎么办？
All right, where am I now?
等一下
All right, hold it!
好了，可以走了
All right, let's go.
转过来…
Swing around now.
手不要放开
Just keep holding hands.
等一下
Hold it!
数到三就放手，还不要放手…
Break it on "3. " Not yet, don't break it.
一
二
三，进车子里
Go!
我们成功了！
Fuck, we did it!
We did it!
祝我们好运！
Wish us luck!
再见
我放了一人质了
You got your one.
跟着我的车
Follow my car.
帮我接甘尼迪机场　　　沙尔…
Get me Kennedy.
沙尔，我们成功了！
We did it!
我们成功了！
I'll be a son of a bitch! We did it!
按喇叭，我们走吧！
Okay, let's move. Come on, honk the horn.
沙尔，帮个忙
Do me a favor, will you?
把枪指别的地方，如果路上颠簸，枪容易走火
Keep the gun pointed up. We hit a bump, it'll go off.
你们好了吗？
You set out there?
我们要准备离开这儿
We're leaving now.
一路上不准有任何的麻烦
We want no trouble en route.
路口都安排好了？
Intersection check?
好…我们现在就要出发
We'll be starting up right now.
10－4
10-4.
会没事的
It'll be all right.
沙尔，你一定要记得要把枪口向上
You just have to remember to keep the gun pointed up.
他在那里干嘛？
What's he doing?
他在安排事情
He's still got some arrangements to make.
就是这架？没错！
沙尔，看到没？就是那架飞机
Sal, see it? There it is.
糟糕
I forgot!
我忘了问上面有没有吃的
I forgot to ask if they got food on board.
上面会有食物吗？
Do they have food on board?
看，那就是你要求的飞机
Your jet.
人质呢？我们约定好的　　　对
We get one more now. That's the deal.
好，谁要走？　　苏菲雅？
Right. Okay, who goes?
Sylvia?
玛莉亚！
Maria.
我会帮你们祷告的
I'll pray for you.
沙尔
第一次坐飞机…
Because this is your first plane trip...
不要太害怕
...don't be scared, okay?
我刚才想起我一整天都没吃，飞机上会有食物吗？
I didn't eat all day. Will there be any food on board?
飞机上有汉堡，准备好了吗？
There'll be hamburgers. Ready?
沙尔　　　怎样？
要走了喔
Ready to go?
好啊
Yeah.
好，我们走吧
Let's move.
沙尔
我们不想这时候出意外
We don't want any accidents at this point, right?
记得把枪口朝上
Keep your gun pointed up.
你要第一个出来吗？　　我准备好了
Ready to get out first?
Ready.
别射我
Don't shoot me.
手脚张开
Now spread them!
我们已处理完了
We're all secure here.
墨飞会在车子里报告
Murphy will report from the car.
你来报告
You make the report.
把枪收起来
Put the gun down.
退后
Back off.
起来，桑尼
Get up now, Sonny.
你被逮捕了
You're under arrest.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你有权请律师为你辩护
You have the right to an attorney during your interrogation.
你所说的任何话都会做为呈堂证供
Anything you say can and will be used against you in a court of law.
若你无法负担律师费用
If you cannot afford to hire a lawyer...
政府会在审问前，指派你的辩护律师
...one will be appointed to represent you if you wish one.
沙登探长，可否麻烦你待在这儿
Agent Sheldon, would you please remain on the apron...
直到所有人质都进入航站大厦为止？
...until the hostages are well inside the terminal?
重复
Repeat:
沙登探长，可否麻烦你待在这儿
Agent Sheldon, would you please remain on the apron...
直到所有人质都进入航站大厦为止？
...until the hostages are well inside the terminal?
是，我收到了，我们会守在这儿
Yeah, I got you. We'll hold here.
桑尼瓦基克在联邦监狱里服刑二十年
安祺瓦基克和她的小孩靠领福利金生活
礼昂谢摩现在已经变为女人，住在纽约市